Well, hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
嗯，大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name's Erica.
我是Erica。
And I'm Marco.
我是Marco。
So, Marco, how are you doing today?
那么，Marco，你今天怎么样？
I'm doing great and I'm really looking forward to our lesson because we're going to the eye
我很好，而且我很期待今天的课程，因为我们要去眼科
doctor today.
医生那里。
Okay, so we've got an elementary lesson about going to the eye doctor.
好的，我们有一节关于看眼科医生的初级课程。
Yes.
是的。
Well, let's get started then with our vocabulary preview.
那么，我们就从词汇预览开始吧。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
We have three words today in our vocabulary preview.
今天的词汇预览中有三个单词。
All three words come from our dialogue.
这三个单词都来自我们的对话。
Our first word is struggle.
第一个单词是struggle。
Struggle.
Struggle。
So, Marco, when I struggle to do something, what does that mean?
那么，Marco，当我struggle去做某事时，那是什么意思？
It means it's difficult.
意思是很难。
It means that you have a hard time so you can't really do it very quickly.
意思是做起来很费劲，不能很快完成。
So you have to try really hard.
所以你必须非常努力。
You have to try really hard.
你必须非常努力。
Yeah, to do something that's difficult.
是的，去做一件困难的事。
Yes.
对。
Okay, our next word is blurry.
好的，下一个词是blurry。
Blurry.
Blurry。
B-L-U-R-R-Y.
B-L-U-R-R-Y。
Blurry.
Blurry。
Whenever something is blurry, you can't really see it well.
当某样东西模糊时，你看不太清楚。
It's not clear.
不清晰。
Right.
对。
That's right.
没错。
Everything will be blurry.
所有东西都会是模糊的。
Okay, and our final word is prescription.
好的，最后一个词是prescription。
Prescription.
Prescription。
Often, when you go to the doctor and you need some medicine, he writes out a prescription.
通常，当你去看医生需要开药时，他会写一张处方。
Right.
对。
It's like a paper that says all the medicine that you need and then you can go to the drug
就像一张纸，上面写着所有你需要的药，然后你可以去药店
store and buy it.
买药。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so those three words you'll hear in today's dialogue and I think it's time we
好的，这三个词你会在今天的对话中听到，我想是时候
listen to the dialogue.
听对话了。
Hello, Arthur.
你好，亚瑟。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
Hey, Doc.
嘿，医生。
Well, I think I might need glasses.
嗯，我想我可能需要配眼镜。
I'm getting headaches and I really struggle to see things that are far away.
我最近头疼，而且看远处的东西很费劲。
But I've always had 20-20 vision.
但我以前视力一直是2.0。
Sounds like you might be farsighted.
听起来你可能是远视。
Okay, then cover your left eye and read the chart in front of you.
好的，那么遮住你的左眼，读你面前的视力表。
X-E-R-3?
X-E-R-3？
Question mark.
问号。
And I can't quite make out the other symbol, but I think it's the peace sign.
另一个符号我看不太清，但我觉得是和平标志。
Wow, Arthur, you're as blind as a bat.
哇，亚瑟，你真是瞎得像蝙蝠一样。
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
My vision is really blurry at times.
我的视力有时真的很模糊。
Okay, then.
那好吧。
Head over to the other room and pick out some frames while I fill out your prescription.
去另一个房间挑些镜框，我帮你开处方。
Thanks, Doc.
谢谢，医生。
Arthur, that's the bathroom.
亚瑟，那是洗手间。
Well, this guy really has poor vision, hey?
这家伙视力真差，是吧？
Well, actually, you know what?
嗯，其实你知道吗？
I've walked into the bathroom, the men's bathroom, actually, instead of the women's
我走进了洗手间，实际上是男洗手间，而不是女
bathroom and that's not because I wasn't wearing my glasses.
洗手间，那可不是因为没戴眼镜。
It's because you weren't paying attention.
那是因为你没注意。
That's true.
没错。
Okay, let's take a look today at our language takeaway.
好的，今天我们来看看语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
The first word on our language takeaway for today is 20-20 vision.
今天语言要点的第一个词是“20-20 vision”。
20-20 vision.
20-20 vision。
If I have 20-20 vision...
如果我有20-20 vision...
It means that you have perfect vision.
那意味着你的视力完美。
Which I do not have.
而我没有。
No, me neither.
不，我也没有。
So I usually wear glasses as well.
所以我也经常戴眼镜。
But yeah, people that have 20-20 vision don't need glasses.
但没错，有20-20视力的人不需要眼镜。
They can see clearly.
他们能看得很清楚。
And perfectly.
而且非常完美。
Yeah.
是的。
Next word is far-sighted.
下一个词是远视。
Far-sighted.
远视。
So, if I'm far-sighted, I can't see very well, right?
所以，如果我是远视，我看不太清楚，对吧？
So if you're far-sighted, you can't see things that are near.
所以如果你远视，你看不清近处的东西。
So you can see things that are far away, but things that are close are blurry.
所以你能看清远处的东西，但近处的东西是模糊的。
Okay.
好的。
And the opposite would be?
那相反的情况是？
Near-sighted.
近视。
And which is?
那是怎样的？
You can see things that are close well.
你能很好地看清近处的东西。
But not far.
但远处不行。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Far-sighted and near-sighted.
远视和近视。
Okay.
好的。
So our next word is make out.
所以我们的下一个词是“make out”。
Make out.
Make out。
That's kind of a funny little phrase.
这个短语有点有趣。
And let's listen to a few examples of this phrase so we can understand how it's used.
让我们听几个这个短语的例子，以便理解它的用法。
Example one.
例子一。
I can't make out what this says.
我看不清这上面写的是什么。
The writing is too small.
字太小了。
Example two.
例子二。
If you look carefully, you can almost make out a few of the stars in the sky.
如果你仔细看，你几乎能辨认出天空中的几颗星星。
Example three.
例子三。
Can you see what's written on the sign there?
你能看到那边牌子上写的是什么吗？
No.
不能。
I can't quite make it out.
我看不太清楚。
Okay.
好的。
So basically, make out is to see clearly.
所以基本上，“make out”就是看清楚的意思。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Make out.
辨认出。
To see.
看见。
Okay.
好的。
And our last word for language takeaway today is blind as a bat.
今天语言小课堂的最后一个词是“像蝙蝠一样瞎”。
Blind as a bat.
像蝙蝠一样瞎。
So this is a really funny sounding expression.
这个表达听起来很有趣。
One of these weird English idioms.
是那些奇怪的英语习语之一。
Yeah.
是的。
It's a really common expression that just means that you can't see.
这是一个很常见的表达，意思就是你看不见。
Exactly.
没错。
So it's not like you actually are blind, right?
它不是说你真的瞎了，对吧？
But you just really can't see very well.
只是你看不太清楚。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
好吧。
We saw four great words today in our language takeaway.
今天语言小课堂我们学了四个很棒的词。
Now I think we can listen to our dialogue another time.
现在我觉得我们可以再听一遍对话。
But this time, it's going to be slower so we can pick up all these great words that
但这次会慢一些，这样我们就能掌握刚才讨论的
we just talked about.
这些好词了。
Hello, Arthur.
你好，亚瑟。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
Hey, Doc.
嘿，医生。
Well, I think I might need glasses.
嗯，我想我可能需要眼镜。
I'm getting headaches and I really struggle to see things that are far away.
我头疼，而且看远处的东西很费劲。
But I've always had 20-20 vision.
但我以前视力一直是2.0。
Sounds like you may be farsighted.
听起来你可能是远视。
Okay, then.
好的，那么。
Cover your left eye and read the chart in front of you.
遮住你的左眼，读你面前的视力表。
X, E, R, 3, question mark, and I can't quite make out the other symbol, but I think it's
X、E、R、3、问号，还有一个符号我辨认不太出来，但我觉得
a peace sign.
是和平标志。
Wow, Arthur, you're as blind as a bat.
哇，亚瑟，你真是像蝙蝠一样瞎。
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
My vision is really blurry at times.
我的视力有时候很模糊。
Okay, then.
好的，那么。
Head on over to the other room and pick out some frames while I fill out your prescription.
去另一个房间挑一些镜框，我帮你开处方。
Thanks, Doc.
谢谢，医生。
Arthur, that's the bathroom.
亚瑟，那是洗手间。
All right.
好吧。
Great stuff on our dialogue.
对话内容很棒。
And with this, we can start now with putting it together.
有了这个，我们现在可以开始把它组装起来了。
Putting it together.
把它组装起来。
So we saw a couple of useful phrases in this dialogue, and I think we can show you how
我们在对话中看到了一些有用的短语，我想我们可以向你们展示如何
to use these phrases in a few different ways.
以几种不同的方式使用这些短语。
Right.
没错。
The first one that we have today is, what seems to be.
今天我们第一个短语是，what seems to be。
So we heard in the dialogue, the doctor said, what seems to be the problem.
我们在对话中听到，医生说了，what seems to be the problem。
We can use this same expression in a number of different ways.
我们可以用多种不同的方式使用这个表达。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
Example two.
例子二。
What seems to be the matter?
怎么了？
Example three.
例子三。
What seems to be the trouble?
有什么麻烦吗？
Okay, so with these examples, we can see how we can use the phrase, what seems to be, in
好的，通过这些例子，我们可以看到如何以多种方式使用“what seems to be”这个短语。
many different ways.
很多不同的方式。
Yeah, it's a great way of asking, what's the problem?
是的，这是一种很好的询问“出了什么问题”的方式。
So now, let's take a look at another phrase.
现在，让我们来看另一个短语。
We heard in the dialogue, the doctor said, head on over to the other room.
我们在对话中听到，医生说：“去另一个房间。”
Right.
对。
And with this phrase, head on, we can combine it with other prepositions to indicate another
而且这个短语 head on 可以和其他介词组合，表示另一个
place.
地方。
Exactly.
没错。
Let's hear three examples.
我们来听三个例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Head on in.
进来吧。
Example two.
例子二。
Head on out.
出去吧。
Example three.
例子三。
Head on up.
上去吧。
Okay, so for example, we can say, head on into the house, it's gonna rain soon.
好的，比如我们可以说，快进屋吧，马上要下雨了。
Or we can say, hey guys, let's head on out to the park.
或者我们可以说，嘿，大家，咱们去公园吧。
Or I can also say, head on up to my room, I'll be there in a second.
或者我也可以说，上我房间去吧，我马上就到。
Great.
太好了。
Those are some cool phrases.
这些短语真酷。
Right, and they're real useful.
没错，而且它们很实用。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue and maybe we'll hear them again.
那我们不如听听对话，也许能再听到它们。
Hello Arthur, what seems to be the problem?
你好，亚瑟，有什么问题吗？
Hey Doc.
嘿，医生。
Well, I think I might need glasses.
嗯，我觉得我可能需要配眼镜了。
I'm getting headaches and I really struggle to see things that are far away.
我最近头疼，而且看远处的东西真的很费劲。
But I've always had 20-20 vision.
但我以前视力一直是2.0。
Sounds like you might be farsighted.
听起来你可能是远视。
Okay then, cover your left eye and read the chart in front of you.
好的，那么遮住你的左眼，读你面前的视力表。
X, E, R, 3, question mark, and I can't quite make out the other symbol, but I think it's
X、E、R、3、问号，还有一个符号我看不太清，但我觉得是
the peace sign.
和平标志。
Wow, Arthur, you're as blind as a bat.
哇，亚瑟，你简直跟蝙蝠一样瞎。
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
My vision is really blurry at times.
我的视力有时候真的很模糊。
Okay then, head over to the other room and pick out some frames while I fill out your
好的，那你去另一个房间挑几副镜框，我帮你开
prescription.
处方。
Thanks Doc.
谢谢医生。
Arthur, that's the bathroom.
亚瑟，那是洗手间。
Okay, so talking about going to the eye doctor today, I have a question for our listeners.
好了，今天聊了看眼科医生的事，我有个问题想问我们的听众。
A challenge for our listeners.
给听众们一个挑战。
What's it called when you can't distinguish colors?
分不清颜色叫什么？
So like when you can't tell the difference between red and blue and green.
就是分不清红色、蓝色和绿色。
Right.
对。
So what is that condition called?
这种情况叫什么？
So there's like a technical term.
有一个专业术语。
We want the technical term.
我们要的是专业术语。
So we'll be looking for it on our comments page and be sure to, if you know the answer,
我们会在评论区等答案，如果你知道答案，一定要
post it.
发出来。
At EnglishPod.com.
在EnglishPod.com上。
Also, if you have questions about today's lesson or any other lesson, please come and
另外，如果你对今天的课程或其他课程有疑问，欢迎来
visit our website and ask us.
我们的网站提问。
Yeah, we hope to see you there, but until then it's goodbye.
是啊，希望在那里见到你，但在此之前，再见。